American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIg. 1887-1891 APS.Archives.IIg APS.Archives.IIg
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 7, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Skeat, Walter W. (Walter William), 1835-1912
    Cambridge, [Eng.], A.L.S. 2p. Concerning publications. Declines membership in Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 11, 1887; 9-1/2x7; Mooney, James, 1861-1921
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends his paper on Medical mythology of Ireland.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 12, 1887; 8x5; Johns Hopkins University
    Baltimore, A.L.S.:N.Murray. 1p. Concerning the publication of Prof.A.M. Elliott.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 14, 1887; 8x5; Greene, Wm. H. (William Houston), 1853-1918
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning [Joseph S.Harris ?]. Refers to [F.] Fraley.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 15, 1887; 9x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends report.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 15, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brooklyn Entomological Society
    New York, A.L.S.:Rich[ard] F.Pearsall, librarian. 1p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 15, 1887; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends nomination.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 18, 1887; 11x8-1/2; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.and end. Concerning reduced size of his map.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 19, 1887; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends nomination for his list. Asking for book on petroleum.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 19, 1887; 8x5; Massachusetts Historical Society
    Boston, L.S.:Samuel A.Green,librarian. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to D[aniel G.Brinton], April 19, 1887; 8x5; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end.by D.G.B[rinton]. Concerning the reduced size of [J.J.] Stevenson's map.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 20, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brooklyn Entomological Society
    New York, A.L.S.:R[ichard] F.Pearsall,librarian. 1p.,end. Concerning publications. Refers to articles by [G.H.] Horn.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 20, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Genth, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1820-1893
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning his views on mimetite pseudomorphs contained in his paper on mineralogy. Refers to letter on this subject from A. Brezina.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 20, 1887; 5x3; Gladwin, Edgar F.
    Brooklyn, L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Business matter. Concerning exchanges, autographs, letters.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 22, 1887; 3x5; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    [Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning his appointment to a committee on an entomological paper. Refers to Fraley, Cope, Leidy, and Ryder.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 22, 1887; 8x5; Massachusetts Historical Society
    Boston, A.L.S.:Samuel A.Green,librarian. 2p.and typed end. Concerning donation of publications to MHS library. Refers to H.M.Phillips.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 23, 1887; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Concerning sale of French Rentes [Michaux legacy].
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 23, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for his courtesy.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], April 25, 1887; 8x5; Horsford, Eben Norton, 1818-1893
    Cambridge, [Mass.] A.L.S. 3p.and end. Enc.wanting. Sends proof sheets of [J.] Heckewelder's work. Refers to [D.G.] Brinton, and sends copy of [D.] Zeisberger's dictionary.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 25, 1887; 11x8; T. Sinclair & Son
    Phila., L. 1p.and end. Printing matter.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 26, 1887; 8" x 10"; Haupt, Lewis M. (Lewis Muhlenberg), b. 1844
    President of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Submits communication upon The Physical Phenomena of Harbor Entrances for the Magellanic premium. Enclosed in: "Magellan" to Fraley, April 26, 1887.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 26, 1887; 8" x 11 1/2"; "Magellan."
    President of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 2 pp. Submits communication "with reference to the action of the physical forces upon alluvial coasts" for Magellanic premium.
  - Letter to Mr. Hill, April 27, 1887; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Bloomington, Ind., A.L.S. 1p. and end. signed Phillips; May 16, 1887. Asks for maps sent with his article on glaciation in Wyoming and Lackawanna Valleys. Refers to J.P. Lesley and C.A. Ashburner.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 30, 1887; 11x9; Verein für Vaterländische Naturkunde in Württemberg. Stuttgart. Jahreshefte
    Stuttgart, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:F[erdinand] Krauss. 1p.,end. In German. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to Secretary of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], April 30, 1887 (?); Rowland, Kate Mason, d. 1916
    A.L.S. 2p.
  - Minute, May 4, 1887; 10-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.in hand of Frederick Fraley. 2p.,end. Extract. Concerning the Michaux legacy. [W.] Ruschenberger is mentioned. Cf.Minutes, May 6, 1887. On same sheet as letter from F.Fraley to H.Phillips, May 4 1887.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, May 4, 1887; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Sends insert for the Minutes [relative to the Michaux legacy]. On same sheet is extract of APS Minute, [May 4, 1887].
  - Letter to [George H.] Horn, May 6, [1887]; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 6, 1887; 5x3; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning [John T.] Napier.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 7, 1887; Maisch, John M. (John Michael), 1831-1893
    A.L.S. 1p. american Pharmaceutical Association letterhead.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 7, 1887; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and add., end.by E[lla] M[orison]. Concerning a box he left at the Society.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, May 7, 1887; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the Michaux [legacy] resolutions.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, May 7, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Maisch, John M. (John Michael), 1831-1893
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning publication.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, May 9, 1887; 3x5; Maisch, John M. (John Michael), 1831-1893
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Thanks for information.
  - Letter to Henry Philips [sic], May 12, 1887; 10x8; McCauley, Edward Yorke, 1827-1894
    [Phila.], A.L.S 1p.,end. Asking that G.Selikovitsch's election to Society be delayed until fall.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 13, 1887; 5-1/2x8; Randall, J. S.
    Georgetown, Colo., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning publications. Is compiling publication on minerals of Colorado.0
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, May 17, 1887; 8x5; Cresson, Charles M. (Charles Massey), 1828-1893
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends duplicate application.
  - Note to [Henry Phillips], May 18, 1887; 4-1/2x5; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.N.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Read and approved [W.] Blasius' paper.
  - Note to [Henry Phillips], May 18, 1887; 5-1/2x2-1/2; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    A.N.S.with initials. 1p.and end. Concerning [meeting of library committee ?].
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 19, 1887; 8x6; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for his attention.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, May 21, 1887; 10x8; Quaritch, Bernard, 1819-1899
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Note to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 24, 1887; 6-1/2x5; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    A.N.S. 1p.,end.,and add. Asking for publication.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 25, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. He has submitted a plan of investigation of his paper on Lemurine reversion [in human dentition] to [G.H.] Horn.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 28, 1887; 9-1/2x6; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Approves of [E.D.] Cope's paper for publication in the Proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 28, 1887; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., Typed L.S.:S[amuel] P.Langley, in another hand. 1p.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 31, 1887; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Asking for announcement of his paper on sea saurians.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 1, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc.wanting. Offers papers on the Mallophaga.
  - Letter to Prof. D[aniel] G.Brinton, June 4, 1887; 8x5; New-York Historical Society
    New York, A.L.S.:J[acob] B.Moore. 1p.,end.by D.G. Brinton. Concerning publication. [H.] Phillips is mentioned in the endorsement.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 4, 1887; 8x5; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the paper he has submitted for publication.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, June 8, 1887; 10x8; Ashburner, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1854-1889
    Pittsburgh, A.L.S. 1p. Sends new address. Refers to [F.] Fraley.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], June 8, 1887; 10x7-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila. A.L.S. 2p.and add. Enc.wanting. Encloses sketch and material for his paper on Triassic vertebrata. Refers to [D.] Brinton.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, June 9, 1887; 8x5; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerning participation of pre-Revolutionary societies of Philadelphia in centennial celebration of the Constitution.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 9, 1887; 8x5; New-York Historical Society
    New York, A.L.S.:J[acob] B.Moore,librarian. 1p. Missing volume has been found.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G. Brinton, June 9, 1887; 3x5; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S.with initial. 1p.and add. Asking to see him concerning [E.D.] Cope
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 10, 1887; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.and add. Asking for his sketch and specimens.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 10, [1887]; Thomson, William
    A.L.S. 1p. encloses photograph. Enclosure wanting.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 13, 1887; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.and add. Concerning the second plate for his paper.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 15, 1887; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Royal Society of Edinburgh
    [Edinburgh], L.on postal card S.:P[eter] G.Tait. 1p., end.,and add. Thanks for publication.
  - Memorandum:, June 17, 1887; 8x5; Geismar, Jacob
    received of A.P.S., specimens belonging to Prof.[E.D.] Cope; D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, June 19, 1887; 6x4; Sergi, Giuseppe, 1841-1936
    [Rome], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Thanks for publications. Sends photographs.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 20, 1887; 3x5; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    [Phila.,] A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Says that [W.V.] Mckean and others want a postponement until more reasonable weather.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 20, 1887; 10x7-1/2; Geological Survey (U.S.)
    Wash.,D.C., Typed L.S.:J[ohn] B.Marcou. 1p.,end. Asking for a book by Bartram.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 21, 1887; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Printing matter.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], June 21, 1887; 9-1/2x5-1/2; G. & B. Westermann Brothers
    New York, L. 2p. Concerning publication.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G.Brinton, June 26, 1887; 9-1/2x6-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerning his paper.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], June 30, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Benjamin, Marcus, 1857-1932
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning picture and autograph of Robert Hare. Refers to Judge Hare, and [F.] Fraley.
  - Letter to Mr. Price, June 30, 1887, 1888; 8x5; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Dr.of L. 1p.,end. Concerning the Society's reports on Volapük.
    Filed under June 30, 1888.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 1, 1887; 3x5; Boston Society of Natural History
    [Boston], L.on postal card S.:Edw[ard] Burgess,secretary. 1p.and add. Asking for missing pages to Society's volume.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, July 6?, 1887; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning meeting of officers and Council in connection with centennial celebration of the Constitution.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 7, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Bank of North America
    Phila., A.L.S.:J[ohn] H.Watt. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends the Society a History of Bank of North America.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, July 8, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Ashburner, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1854-1889
    Pittsburgh, A.L.S. 1p. Offers resolution appointing the president to represent the Society at the centennial celebration of the Constitution.
  - Letter to F[rederick] Fraley, July 8, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., L.S. 2p. Concerning the dinner [relative to the centennial celebration of the Constitution]
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 8, 1887; 3x5; Subscription news co.
    Chicago, L.on postal card. 1p.and add. Concerning publications.
  - Resolution of Council appointing the President to represent Society in connection with the arrangements for the centennial celebration of the Constitution, July 9, 1887; 9x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D. 2p.and end.by Ruschenberger, Fraley, Law, and Phillips. Copy.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 12, 1887; 8-1/2x5; Servicio Meteorológico Mexicano
    Printed L.S.:Miguel Pérez. 2p.,end. Order for publications.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 15, 1887; 8x5; Baird, Henry Martyn, 1832-1906
    Yonkers, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends photograph for the Society's album.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 16, 1887; 10x8; Trübner & Co.
    London, L. 1p. Order for publication by E.D.Cope.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 19, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Singleton, Esther, d. 1930
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning R.M.S.Jackson.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, July 25, 1887; 9-1/2x6; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. Declines to approve Sulerkovitch's [G. Selikovitsch's] article for publication.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], July 29, 1887; 8x5; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Asking for return of his manuscript.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Aug. 1, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Lesley, J. P. (J. Peter), 1819-1903
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asking him to give bearer publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Aug. 10, 1887; 10x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S.:W[illia]m B.Taylor. 1p.,end. Concerning Charles Rau.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 17, 1887; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Smithsonian Institution. Bureau of American Ethnology
    Wash., D.C., Printed L.S.:James C.Pilling. 2p. Asking permission to examine Society's manuscripts on the Iroquois Indians for the Bureau's planned series on North American languages. Refers to [D.G.] Brinton.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips ?], Aug. 17, 1887; 9x5-1/2; Stavely, J. Thomas
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asking for meeting.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Aug. 18, 1887; 10x8; Thorburn, John
    Ottawa, A.L.S. 1p. Asking for copy of Phillips' article on the runic inscription at Yarmouth, N.S.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Aug. 24, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Society of Antiquaries of London
    A.L.S.:E.C.Ireland. 1p. Order for publications.
  - Note to the American philosophical society, Aug. 26, 1887; 3-1/2x9; Hyrtl, Joseph, 1811-1894
    [Vienna,]. N.in 3rd.P. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Returning publications on account of his blindness.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Aug. 28, 1887; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila], A.L.S. 1p. Asking him to send F.D.Stone a list of the resident members of the Society.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Aug. 31, 1887; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Smithsonian Institution. Bureau of American Ethnology
    Wash.,D.C., Typed L.S.:James C.Pilling. 1p. Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 1, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning sale of French Rents [Michaux legacy].
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 5, 1887; 9x5-1/2; Stubbs, Charles H.
    Wakefield, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Concerning offer of plaster casts of boundary monuments on Mason and Dixon's line.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 5, 1887; 8x5; Stokes, Alfred C.
    Trenton, A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Asking for publication of his paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 7, 1887; 8x6-1/2; Wagner Free Institute of Science
    Phila., A.L.S.:Thomas L.Montgomery,actuary. 1p. and add.,end. Asking him to give bearer the package.
  - Letter to Prof. E[dwin] J.Houston, Sept. 7, 1887; 8x5; McKean, W. V. (William Vincent), 1820-1902
    Phila., L.S. 1p.and end. Concerning meeting of library committee.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Sept. 8, 1887; 8x5; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning meeting of library committee.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Sept. 9, 1887; 3x5; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Brunswick, Me., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning proofs of his paper.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Sept. 12, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Ashburner, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1854-1889
    West Baden, Ind., A.L.S. 1p. Asking for cards to Society's reception.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 13, 1887; 8x5; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning [library] committee.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Sept. 21, 1887; 8x5; Burk, Jesse Young, ca. 1840-1904
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment to prepare obituary of [W.B.] Stevens.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Sept. 21, 1887; 8x5; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.wanting. Sends proof and drawing.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], Sept. 22, 1887; 8x5; Holmes, J. A. (Joseph Austin), 1859-1915
    Chapel Hill, A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerning loan of plates for his state's geological survey. Refers to W.C. Kerr, and [J.P.] Lesley.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Sept. 23, 1887; 8x5; Leidy, Joseph, 1823-1891
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning his obituary of Isaac Lea. On same sheet is letter from F.Fraley to H.Phillips, Sept.24, 1887.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips, Sept. 23, 1887; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end.,and end. Enc.wanting. Offers article [by Samuel Garman] for publication.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Sept. 24, 1887; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking about [P.] Garrett's obituary of [P.E.] Chase. On same sheet as letter from J.Leidy to [F.] Fraley, Sept.23, 1887.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 26, 1887; 10x8; Ely, E. D.
    Canton, O., A.L.S. 1p.and end.,and add. Asking for publication by J.P.Lesley.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Sept. 26, 1887; 10x8; Ludlow, Nicoll, 1842-1915
    San Francisco, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Asking for [E.Y.] McCauley's Egyptian dictionary. Refers to [H]. Gorringe.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Sept. 27, 1887; 8x5; Leidy, Joseph, 1823-1891
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning his obituary of Isaac Lea. Refers to [H.] Phillips.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Sept. 27, 1887; 8x5; Morison, Ella M.
    A.L.S. 1p. She will be down to the library on Saturday.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Sept. 28, 1887; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Mutilated with crayon. Asking for announcement of his remarks on [Lemurine reversion in] human dentition.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Sept. 29, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Eigenmann, Carl H., 1863-1927
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Concerning publications on ichthyology.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Sept. 30, 1887; 5x3; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Asking why he has not received notices of meetings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 6, 1887; 3x5; Eigenmann, Carl H., 1863-1927
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct. 6, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Thayer, Russell
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Concerning [L.Haupt's] paper for the Magellanic premium. Bache, Lehman, Thayer, Winsor, and Cleemann are mentioned in the endorsement.
  - Letter to Prof. Henry Phillips, Oct. 7, 1887; 3x5; Stokes, Alfred C.
    Trenton, A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Asking for return of his sketches.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct. 8, 1887; 8x5; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Asking if he may prepare obituary of N. Randolph.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Oct. 10, 1887; 10x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Agrees to prepare obituary of [N.] Randolph. Enclosed originally in letter from Fred. Fraley to H.Phillips, Oct.12, 1887.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 11, 1887; 8x5; Ludlow, Nicoll, 1842-1915
    San Francisco, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Enc.wanting. Sends postage for [E.Y.] McCauley's [Egyptian] dictionary.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 11, 1887; 8x5-1/2; Samuel, J. Bunford
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asking where he found the "sextant" [?].
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 12, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.and end. Enc. Sends [J.] Rothrock's acceptance of the appointment to prepare obituary of [N.] Randolph. Refers to [C.] Oliver. For enclosure, see letter from J.T. Rothrock to [F.] Fraley, Oct.10, 1887.
  - Letter to H.M. Phillips [Henry Phillips], Oct. 15, 1887; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Says that the manuscript on Artiodactyla is complete.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 15, 1887; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts
    Phila., A.L.S.:Geo[rge] Corliss,secretary. 1p. Says that the pictures will be called for on November 21.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Oct.16, 1887; 10-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning obituary of N. Randolph. Refers to [C.] Oliver and [J.] Rothrock.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], Oct. 17, 1887; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning [G.] Meneghini. Refers to G.Capellini and J.J.Stevenson.
  - Letter to H.M. Phillips [Henry Phillips], Oct. 18, 1887; 8x5; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for M.Robinson's obituary of H. Seybert.
  - Letter to Henry Philip [Henry Phillips], Oct. 20, 1887; 9-1/2x6; American district telegraph company
    Phila., L. 1p. Business matter.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 21, 1887; 3x5; Spear, James
    [Phila.], L.S. 1p.and add. Concerning book supports.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct. 24, 1887; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924